const e="accounting",t=200,o=47,a=[{id:345,question:"The source document used to make entries in the purchases day book is",option:{a:"debit note",b:"credit note",c:"invoice",d:"receipt"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:346,question:"book that contains individual accounts of suppliers is the",option:{a:"purchases ledger",b:"general ledger",c:"nominal ledger",d:"sales ledger"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:347,question:"In the operation of an imprest system of petty cash, the",option:{a:"petty cashier pays all expenses",b:"petty cashier pays money to the accountant",c:"petty cashier regularly begins each period with the same amount of money",d:"main cashier accounts to the petty cashier for some expenses made by him"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:348,question:"An example of a credit entry in a profit and loss account is",option:{a:"carriage inwards",b:"carriage outwards",c:"discounts allowed",d:"discounts received"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:349,question:"Which of the following subsidiary books involves cash movement?",option:{a:"Sales day book",b:"Purchases day book",c:"Returns inwards book",d:"Petty cash book"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:350,question:"The accounting treatment for a dishonoured cheque is; debit",option:{a:"Customer’s Account; Credit Bank Account",b:"Bank Account; Credit Customer’s Account",c:"Customer’s Account; Credit Sales Account",d:"Sales Account; Credit Customer’s Account\\"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:351,question:"Net turnover is referred to as",option:{a:"purchases",b:"assets",c:"sales",d:"profits"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:352,question:"Which of the following transactions will result in disagreement between the cash book and the bank statement?",option:{a:"Selling of goods on credit to a customer",b:"Withdrawal of goods by the proprietor for his personal use",c:"Cheque paid directly into the bank account by a customer",d:"Omission of purchases received from a supplier on credit"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:353,question:"Purchases Account is overcast by N200, while Wages Account is under cast by N200. This is",option:{a:"an error of omission",b:"a compensating error",c:"an error of commission",d:"an error of principle"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:354,question:"Which of the following is used to record the disposal of a fixed asset?",option:{a:"Journal  Proper",b:"Petty  Cash  Book",c:"Sales Day Book",d:"Purchases Day Book"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:355,question:"The annual depreciation is",option:{a:"N9,000",b:"N8,500",c:"N8,000",d:"N6,500"},section:"Use the following information to answer question:	Cost of motor vehicle-1/1/12 [ 85,000 ];  Residual value [ 5,000 ]; Estimated useful lifespan 10 years . The business makes use of the straight line method for 	providing depreciation.",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:356,question:"The accumulated depreciation as at 31/12/2013 is",option:{a:"N18,500",b:"N17,000",c:"N16,000",d:"N8,000"},section:"Use the following information to answer question:	Cost of motor vehicle-1/1/12 [ 85,000 ];  Residual value [ 5,000 ]; Estimated useful lifespan 10 years . The business makes use of the straight line method for 	providing depreciation.",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:357,question:"An error of principle is made, if",option:{a:"an entry has been made in the wrong class of account",b:"a transaction has been completely omitted",c:"an entry has been made on the wrong side of the two accounts concerned",d:"a transaction is entered in both accounts for the wrong amount"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:358,question:"Which of the following is entered in the general journal?",option:{a:"Purchase of goods",b:"Sale of goods on credit",c:"Returns inwards",d:"Acquisition of fixed assets"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:359,question:"The cost of carriage outward is classified as",option:{a:"a selling and distribution expense",b:"an administrative expense",c:"a trading expense",d:"a finance expense"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:360,question:"The purchase of ten ceiling fans by Akpan Electronic Enterprises will be recorded as",option:{a:"an acquisition of fixed asset",b:"an expense in its general office expense account",c:"part of capital in the capital account",d:"an acquisition of stock"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:361,question:"Which of the following accounts would appear in the nominal ledger?  (I)  Sanison’s account (a debtor)  ( II) Motor vehicle account (III) Sales account  (IV)  Rent and rates account",option:{a:"I, II and III only",b:"I, III and IV only",c:"II, III and IV only",d:"Ill and IV only"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:362,question:"The sum of direct cost in a manufacturing account is",option:{a:"production cost",b:"prime cost",c:"total cost",d:"finance cost"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:363,question:"Net profit in a business is",option:{a:"the amount of money taken out of the business by the owner",b:"the cash in the business bank account",c:"the difference between sales and cost of sales",d:"sale revenue less cost of sales and expenses"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:364,question:"An example of a self-balancing account is the",option:{a:"suspense account",b:"creditor’s account",c:"control account",d:"debtor’s accoun"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:365,question:"The gross profit is",option:{a:"GHc/  2,160,000",b:"GHc/ 1440,000",c:"GHc/ 1,080,000",d:"GHc/ 720,000"},section:"Use the following information to answer question: The total sales of a business was GHc/ 2,160,000. The average mark-up for the year was 50%.",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:366,question:"The cost of sales is",option:{a:"GHc/  2,160,000t",b:"GHc/ 1440,000",c:"GHc/ 1,080,000",d:"GHc/  720,000"},section:"Use the following information to answer question: The total sales of a business was GHc/ 2,160,000. The average mark-up for the year was 50%.",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:367,question:"Which of the following is not an administrative expenses in a 	manufacturing organization?",option:{a:"Discounts allowed",b:"Office electricity",c:"Stationery",d:"Insurance"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:368,question:"When an asset is sold, the entries for the accumulated depreciation are: debit",option:{a:"Asset Disposal Account; credit Provision for Depreciation Account.",b:"Provision for Depreciation Account; Credit Asset Disposal Account",c:"Fixed Asset Account; Credit Asset Disposal Account",d:"Asset Disposal Account; Credit Fixed Asset Account"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:369,question:"A petty cash account has an imprest of D28,000. The account has a debit balance of D5.000. How much cash is needed to restore the imprest?",option:{a:"D33,000",b:"D28,000",c:"D23,000",d:"D5,000"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:370,question:"In a not - for - profit making organization, when the total income 	is less than the total expenditure, the difference is a",option:{a:"surplus",b:"shortfall",c:"loss",d:"deficit"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:371,question:"The accounting concept underlying the treatment of personal expenses of the business owner as drawing is",option:{a:"periodicity",b:"accrual",c:"entity",d:"materiality"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:372,question:"Which of the following items is not contained in the Receipts and Payments Account?",option:{a:"Subscription paid in advance",b:"tock paid for in advance",c:"Outstanding wages and salaries",d:"Donations"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:373,question:"The concept that states that a business should not lay claim to any profits before it is earned with reasonable certainty is",option:{a:"consistency concept",b:"prudence concept",c:"accrual concept",d:"going concern concept"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:374,question:"When shares are issued above their nominal value, the 	excess above the nominal value is",option:{a:"credited to Profit and Loss Account",b:"debited to Share Premium Account",c:"credited to Share Capital Account",d:"credited to share Premium Account"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:375,question:"Shares issued below nominal value are referred to as shares at",option:{a:"premium",b:"discount",c:"face value",d:"cumulative value"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:376,question:"The accounting ratio used to measure the average number of days for which suppliers remain unpaid is",option:{a:"stock turnover",b:"creditors’ payment period",c:"debtors collection period",d:"return on capital employed"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:377,question:"When the purchase consideration exceeds the value of business, the difference is",option:{a:"profit",b:"discount",c:"goodwill",d:"reserve"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:378,question:"The primary classification of government expenditure is based on",option:{a:"Programs",b:"funds",c:"activity",d:"project"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:379,question:"An example of input device of a computer is",option:{a:"an optical character reader",b:"a graph plotter",c:"a visual display unit",d:"printer"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:380,question:"The accounting concept which states that expenditure involving insignificant amounts should be regarded as expenses and not assets is",option:{a:"business entity",b:"materiality",c:"dual aspect",d:"realization"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:381,question:"A company made a net profit of N2,000,000 for the year and its net profit percentage is 25%. What is the total sales   for the year?",option:{a:"N8,000,000",b:"N6,000,000",c:"N800,000",d:"N500,000"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:382,question:"Which of the following information is recorded in the returns outwards book?",option:{a:"Goods purchased on credit and subsequently returned to supplier",b:"Fixed asset bought on credit and subsequently returned to supplier",c:"Cash payment received from a customer and subsequently returned to supplier",d:"Goods sold to a customer and subsequently returned to the business."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:383,question:"Calculate the stock figure to be included in the balance sheet at the year end.",option:{a:"D408,000",b:"D346,000",c:"D284,000",d:"D62,000"},section:" Use the following information to answer question: Branch stock account (at selling price)  D346,000 - debit Branch mark-up account D62,000 - debit",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:384,question:"The concept applied in answering question 42 above is",option:{a:"matching",b:"consistency",c:"prudence",d:"entity"},section:" Use the following information to answer question: Branch stock account (at selling price)  D346,000 - debit Branch mark-up account D62,000 - debit",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:385,question:"Subscriptions in advance is classified in the balance sheet as",option:{a:"an asset",b:"a liability",c:"a deficit",d:"a surplus"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:386,question:"Which of the following items is not treated in the Profit and Loss Account?",option:{a:"Office expenses",b:"Salaries and allowances",c:"Carriage inwards",d:"Discounts allowed"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:387,question:"The document prepared by a local/district government to present its annual estimates for a planning period is",option:{a:"a balance sheet",b:"budget",c:"an income and expenditure account",d:"a cash book"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:388,question:"A manufacturing account is drawn up by",option:{a:"firms providing personal services",b:"firms engaged solely in buying and selling of goods",c:"firms which make and sell articles",d:"non - trading organization."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:389,question:"Which of the following is not a factory overhead cost?",option:{a:"Manufacturing wages",b:"Factory rent",c:"Depreciation of machinery",d:"Salary of factory guard"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:390,question:"A collection of fields relating to one logically definable unit of business information is known as",option:{a:"data",b:"character",c:"byte",d:"record"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:391,question:"The principle of double entry book - keeping states that",option:{a:"every debtor must have a creditor",b:"every account debited must be immediately credited",c:"for every debit entry, there must be a corresponding credit entry",d:"for every double debit, there must be a double credit."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"}],s={subject:e,status:200,total:47,data:a};export{a as data,s as default,t as status,e as subject,o as total};
